Pharaoh Giles

General Laborer - Labor Solutions

Milwaukee, WI pharaohlgiles@gmail.com - (414) 215-8604

I am a highly driven worker with a hunger for productivity. I have worked in various fields, though I generally lean more in the field of production as well as physical labor. Over the years I have acquired a plethora of skills that makes me a great candidate for various positions. I am currently in college pursuing an Associate's degree in Welding Technology

WORK EXPERIENCE

General Laborer

Labor Solutions - Milwaukee. WI -

August 2018 to Present

- Pack containers and re-pack damaged containers.
- Move freight, stock, or other materials to and from storage or production areas, loading docks, delivery vehicles, ships, or containers, by hand or using trucks, tractors, or other equipment.
- Stack cargo in locations such as transit sheds or in holds of ships as directed, using pallets or cargo boards.

General Laborer

Sites Staffing - Milwaukee, WI -

August 2017 to August 2018

- Stack cargo in locations such as transit sheds or in holds of ships as directed, using pallets or cargo boards.
- Sort cargo before loading and unloading.
- Pack containers and re-pack damaged containers.
- Move freight, stock, or other materials to and from storage or production areas, loading docks, delivery vehicles, ships, or containers, by hand or using trucks, tractors, or other equipment.

General Cleaner

ABM Onsite Services - Milwaukee, WI -

January 2016 to January 2017

- Clean building floors by sweeping, mopping, scrubbing, or vacuuming.
- Clean laboratory equipment, such as glassware or metal instruments, using solvents, brushes, rags, or power cleaning equipment.
- Clean windows, glass partitions, or mirrors, using soapy water or other cleaners, sponges, or squeegees.
- Dust furniture, walls, machines, or equipment.

- Follow procedures for the use of chemical cleaners and power equipment to prevent damage to floors and fixtures.
- Gather and empty trash.
- Mix water and detergents or acids in containers to prepare cleaning solutions, according to specifications.
- Monitor building security and safety by performing tasks such as locking doors after operating hours or checking electrical appliance use to ensure that hazards are not created.
- Notify managers concerning the need for major repairs or additions to building operating systems.
- Service, clean, or supply restrooms.
- Set up, arrange, or remove decorations, tables, chairs, ladders, or scaffolding to prepare facilities for events, such as banquets or meetings.

Account Manager/Sales Representative

All Green Corporation - Waukesha, WI -

April 2013 to September 2015

- Manage Customer Accounts
- Meet Weekly Quota of \$2500 in sales
- Up-sale current customers
- Visit Properties & Damp; give quotes
- Handle Customer Inquiries & Department of the Customer
- Train New Representatives

Apprentice Welder

Vanguard Sculpture Services - Milwaukee, WI -

June 2009 to September 2015

- Advertise & amp; Sell pieces
- Analyze engineering drawings, blueprints, specifications, sketches, work orders, and material safety data sheets to plan layout, assembly, and welding operations.
- Check grooves, angles, or gap allowances, using micrometers, calipers, and precision measuring instruments.
- Chip or grind off excess weld, slag, or spatter, using hand scrapers or power chippers, portable grinders, or arc-cutting equipment.
- Clamp, hold, tack-weld, heat-bend, grind or bolt component parts to obtain required configurations and positions for welding.
- Clean or degrease parts, using wire brushes, portable grinders, or chemical baths.
- Connect and turn regulator valves to activate and adjust gas flow and pressure so that desired flames are obtained.
- Detect faulty operation of equipment or defective materials and notify supervisors.
- Develop templates and models for welding projects, using mathematical calculations based on blueprint information.
- Dismantle metal assemblies or cut scrap metal, using thermal-cutting equipment such as flame-cutting torches or plasma-arc equipment.
- Estimate materials needed for production and manufacturing and maintain required stocks of materials.

- Examine workpieces for defects and measure workpieces with straightedges or templates to ensure conformance with specifications.
- Guide and direct flames or electrodes on or across workpieces to straighten, bend, melt, or build up metal.
- Hammer out bulges or bends in metal workpieces.
- Lay out, position, align, and secure parts and assemblies prior to assembly, using straightedges, combination squares, calipers, and rulers.
- Mark or tag material with proper job number, piece marks, and other identifying marks as required.
- Operate brazing and soldering equipment.
- Operate safety equipment and use safe work habits.
- Position and secure workpieces, using hoists, cranes, wire, and banding machines or hand tools.
- Preheat workpieces prior to welding or bending, using torches or heating furnaces.
- Prepare all material surfaces to be welded, ensuring that there is no loose or thick scale, slag, rust, moisture, grease, or other foreign matter.
- Remove rough spots from workpieces, using portable grinders, hand files, or scrapers.
- Repair products by dismantling, straightening, reshaping, and reassembling parts, using cutting torches, straightening presses, and hand tools.
- Set up and use ladders and scaffolding as necessary to complete work.
- Signal crane operators to move large workpieces.
- Use fire suppression methods in industrial emergencies.
- Weld components in flat, vertical, or overhead positions.

Dishwasher

Water Street Brewery - Milwaukee, WI -

April 2017

- Personal Business
- Wholesale Vacation Packages
- Advertise & Dromote Business Concept
- Recruit New Agents
- Train New Recruits
- Host Sales Parties & Damp; Events

EDUCATION

Obtaining Associate's Degree in Welding Technology

Milwaukee Area Technical College

August 2018 to Present

GED

Milwaukee Area Technical College

August 2018 to August 2018

SKILLS

SANDBLASTING (5 years), WELDING (6 years), GRINDERS (6 years), METAL CUTTING (6 years), ASSEMBLY (3 years), General Labor (6 years), Construction Laborer (1 year), General Laborer (6 years), Assembly Line (3 years), Warehouse Associate (4 years), Foundry (5 years)

GROUPS

Matc Student Government Official Officer

August 2018 to Present

Official Officer of Student Government Association @ MATC West Allis Campus

President of MATC Student Weld Club

September 2018 to Present

Active President of Milwaukee Area Technical College's Student Welding Club

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

SKILLS

- -5+ years MIG Welding Experience (stainless/mild steel)
- -5+ years TIG Welding Experience (Bronze/Steel)
- -5+ years excessive power tool experience (Hand Drills, cutting discs, grinders, sandblasting, etc)
- Excessive knowledge of assembly & amp; production line procedures
- -Print Reading Experience
- -5+ years Metal Finishing experience (Metal cutting, grinding, polishing & sandblasting)
- -2 years Cleaning Experience (General & Department of the Cleaning)
- -Knowledge of Press Operation
- -Account Management & Sales Experience
- -Excellent Communication Skills-Extremely Fast Learner